[applause and cheering]
>> Let me tell you what each recipients
will receive tonight. Of course, you'll
get your your your plaque, you'll get a
pin, and a number of proclamations. And
the proclamations are from Governor
Wyne,
the State Senate,
the State House, Cuyahoga County,
Cleveland City Council, and the City of
Cleveland. So,
lots of stuff to take home for our
distinguished honorees.
Let's
meet our first honoree of the evening
going to the Cleveland International
Hall of Fame.
She is Lucy Torres.
Lucy
will be inducted by a gentleman you met
earlier tonight,
the president of the Cleveland City
Council, Mr. Blaine Griffin.
Thank you.
I know I had a chance to speak to you
earlier, but this is truly another honor
and a privilege because when you work
with someone, a lot of people don't
realize but you spend the majority of
your life with the people that you work
with and not the people that you live
with sometimes.
So, Lucy Torres is like family to me.
Lucy is the person who took me into the
Puerto Rican and Hispanic community and
indoctrinated me on such a wonderful
culture. I'll never forget her taking me
to some of the clubs and I thought that
they were nightclubs or party centers,
but they weren't. They were places where
families gathered, where the first floor
would have children and young folks, the
second floor would have uh young
professionals, and then you would have
some of the senior folks that would be
playing cards. And she was such an icon
in the community that everywhere that
she went and walked, everybody knew her.
Lucy was responsible for helping me
grow into my personal and professional
self. She's a person who I see her
daughter, that's here today,
that she loves her family.
Her late husband was a phenomenal guy
who we would sit there for hours and
hang out over their house and eat
because she's a great cook, too.
But most of all, Lucy's love for
community and her civic spirit
was something that was unmatched. So,
being with all of these different
directors and having the honor and the
privilege for her to ask me
to fill in for Manny Velez, who's a
police officer who unfortunately
couldn't be here today,
is truly an honor. She was one of the
impetus for making sure that the Puerto
Rican community always had a voice,
always had a voice at the table. She ran
and put together one of the most
impactful committees that made sure that
the Hispanic community always had an
advice on important issues. So, not only
could she throw a good party, she also
knew how to handle the purpose
for the Puerto Rican and Hispanic
community. So, ladies and gentlemen, it
is an honor and a privilege as the
former executive director of the
community relations board and as the
current Cleveland City Council President
to induct my friend, the honorable Lucy
Rodriguez Torrez.
>> [applause and cheering]
[screaming]
>> Pick them up.
Just the award, just the award.
Luce.
I did this picture.
Awesome.
>> Let's give her another round of
applause.
>> [applause]
>> Thank you.
Thank you.
It's an honor for me. Thank you.
Thank you, Ben.
Um I'm privileged to be here
uh tonight and to receive
this recognition.
My community
is a very very important community for
this city.
We have
worked very hard
to put our community
up there.
We are good people.
We are hard worker people
and we are dedicated people.
I would like also to say thank you to my
family, my daughter
Charisse,
my grandchildren
and also my niece, my nephew that are
they always also my children because I
raised them.
They came from Puerto Rico looking for a
better
way to improve themselves and they have.
So at this time what I have to say
is thank you, Lord, for the time that
you have allowed me to be here.
And to all of you, thank you.
>> [applause]
[applause]